"HIDDEN LEAF
NINJUTSU RESEARCH CENTER"
This is the Parasitic Insect
we got from Shino, isn't it?
回収された シノの寄壊蟲か。
Yes.
はい。
What's this?!
何だ!? これは。
(綱手)何だ？
この六角形のパターンは。
What is this hexagonal pattern?!
(シズネ)
はい 研究班からの報告では➡
Well, according the report from
the research team...
シノの寄壊蟲の体液までもが
結晶化していたということです。
It means that even the body fluids of
Shino's Parasitic Insect have crystallized.
I see...
そうか…。
どうしたんです？ 綱手様。
What's the matter, Tsunade-sama?
まさか 本当にあったとはな…。
I never thought it truly existed...
何か ご存じなのですね？
Do you know something about this?
うむ…。
Yes.
(綱手)かつて あらゆる物質を
結晶化させる忍術があると➡
In the past, a rumor had spread
about the existence of a Ninjutsu
that crystallizes all materials.
ウワサが広まったことがある。
人の血液すらも
結晶化してしまうそうだ。
It was said to even crystallize
human blood.
晶遁と呼ばれた その忍術で➡
It's a Ninjutsu technique
called Crystal Style.
一夜のうちに 村ひとつが
消滅したとも➡
It was said that an entire village disappeared
in one night because of it...
言われていたんだが➡
After it happened,
その後 目撃談もなく
単なるウワサと処理されたんだ。
there were no reports by witnesses,
so it was dismissed as rumor.
Then, you're saying that
Crystal Style actually existed?
では その晶遁が
実在していたということですね？
Yes. If we relate the fact that
there were no witnesses for a long time
ああ。
長い間 目撃者もなかったことと➡
今回 カカシたちが接触したことが
結びつくとしたら➡
and the contact that Kakashi
and the others had,
this could possibly be
one of Orochimaru's group.
大蛇丸のコレクションのひとつと
考えられるだろう。
大蛇丸が動き出したと
いうことでしょうか？
Does that mean that Orochimaru
has begun moving?
サスケが 里を出て すでに３年…➡
It's already been three years
since Sasuke left the village.
It's right about the time
when Orochimaru could be reincarnated.
大蛇丸は 転生が可能な時期に
さしかかっているはずだ。
大蛇丸が その準備に
取り掛かったと考えるべきだろう。
We should consider that Orochimaru
has begun making preparations for it.
なんとしてでも
その晶遁忍者を手掛かりに➡
We must use that Crystal Style Ninja
as a lead to...
サスケの居場所を突き止めろ！
to learn Sasuke's whereabouts!
you've gotta be extra careful
mijika ni aru mono
with the things nearest to you
tsuneni ki wo tsukete inai to
you know the closer you get to something
amari ni chika sugite
the tougher it is to see it
miushinatte shimai sou
explain to me this happiness
anata ga saikin taiken shita
that you just got to experience?
shiawase wa ittai nan desu ka
or maybe you're so blessed
megumare sugite ite
that you can't even remember it
omoidasenai kamo
that you stand here now
ima koko ni iru koto
that you still live and breathe
iki wo shite iru koto
I realised that they all were miracles
tada soredake no koto ga
just by themselves
kiseki da to kidzuku
you've gotta be extra careful
mijika ni aru mono
with the things nearest to you
tsuneni ki wo tsukete inai to
you know the closer you get to something
amari ni chika sugite
the tougher it is to see it
miushinatte shimai sou
you know the closer you get to something
the tougher it is to see it
and i'll never take it for granted
it's fine to say you'll never give up
oi tsudzukete kita yume
and to keep chasing your dreams
akiramezu ni susumeyo nante
but the more time you spend talking big
kirei goto wo ieru hodo
the less you get done
nanimo dekicha inai kedo
I will press that handful of courage against my heart
hito nigiri no yuuki wo mune ni
and with its help survive another day
ashita wo ikinuku tame ni
and i'll never take it for granted
let's go
The Labyrinth of
Distorted Reflection
(ヤマト)止まれ。
Halt!
(ヤマト)手はずどおりなら
目印を残して➡
If things were going according to plan,
he would have left some sign.
行ってくれてるはず
なんだけどね。
(サクラ)ここまで
それらしいものには➡
I didn't see anything like that...
気づかなかったけど。
(ナルト)ったくよ 後続班のこと
忘れてんじゃねえだろうな。
Man! They better not have forgotten
about the group behind them!
アンタじゃないんだから。
They're not you, you know!
探索班に 異変があったと
考えるべきでしょ。
We should assume something happened
to the search team!
(ヤマト)サイ。
(サイ)はい。
- Sai.
- Yes?
空から偵察してくれないかな。
Can you do reconnaissance from the sky?
(サイ)わかりました。
Understood.
(サイ)忍法 超獣偽画。
Ninja Art: Super Beast Scroll.
《サイが戻るまで 時間があるな》
We've got some time
until Sai comes back.
ここで ちょっと
待っててくれってばよ。
Wait for me here a while.
任務中でしょ！ どこ行くのよ!?
We're on duty!
Where do you think you're going?
あぁ オシッコだってばよ。
I've gotta pee!
もう…。
Good grief!
探索班らしき姿は 見当たらない。
I don't see anything that looks
like the search team.
椿!?
Camellia?
このすきに もう一回
修業のおさらいやっとかねえと➡
I'd better take this chance to review
my training some more...
さっきのタイミング
忘れちまうってばよ。
I've forgotten the timing I had earlier.
な なんだ？
Huh? What's that?!
お前 この間の。
You're that kid I saw the other day!
やっぱり あんときの。
It is you, after all...
What're you doing here?
こんなところで なにしてんだ？
(幽鬼丸)椿の木は
低いのばかりじゃないんだよ。
Not all camellia trees are short.
Some that grow in the wild are this tall.
自然に生えているのには
こんな高いのもあるんだ。
なに言ってんだよ。 オレだよ オレ。
What're you talking about?
It's me!
You know, from the hot springs!
温泉で ほら。
誰にでも きっと
帰るところがあるんだよ。
Everyone has someplace to go home to.
思ってくれる人がいるところが
帰る場所なんだ。
Wherever someone's thinking of you,
that's where you go home to.
それ オレがお前に教えたことだろ。
Isn't that what I taught you?
そんなことより お前
一人なんじゃねえか？
Never mind that, though.
You're alone, aren't you?
仲間とか家族は？
Where are your friends? Your family?
白い椿が赤くって…➡
The white camellias turned... red...
そしたら
いなくなっちゃったんだ。
Then they disappeared... All of them.
みんな みんな…。
やっぱり 一人なんだな。
Just as I thought, you're all alone,
aren't you?
だったら
オレたちのところに来ないか？
If that's the case,
do you want to come with us?!
一緒にオレたちの里に来いよ。
Come with us to our hometown.
今は任務の途中だけど 終わったら
迎えに来てやるってばよ。
We're on a mission right now,
but when we're done,
we'll come back for you.
((紅蓮 : ちょっと やぼ用ができた。
ここで待ってろ))
Something just came up. Wait here.
待ってなきゃ。
え？
I have to wait...
Huh?!
ボクを思ってくれる人が
いるところが➡
Where there's someone thinking of me,
that's where I go home to.
ボクの帰る場所。
ああ そうだ。
Yes, that's right!
思ってくれてるのかな？
思ってくれてるといいな。
Is there anyone thinking of me?
I hope there is.
ひょっとして
思ってくれてる人がいるのか？
Could it be that
there's someone thinking of you?
熱出したとき
寝ないで看病してくれた。
When I broke out in a fever,
that person cared for me without sleeping.
そうか。 そりゃお前のこと
思ってくれてんじゃねえか？
I see! That shows that person
was thinking of you!
そうだといいな。
I hope so...
いいか ソイツについてけ。
その手を離すんじゃねえぞ。
Listen, follow that person!
Don't let that person go!
うん。
Uh-huh.
シノの蟲？
- Shino's insect?!
- Naruto...
ナルト。
ワリい オレ 任務が…。
Sorry. I'm on a mission...
あれ どこ行ったんだ？
Huh?! Where'd he go?!
でもまあ アイツも
帰るところができたみてえだし。
Oh well, it seems he has
a place to go home to.
シノの寄壊蟲を発見した。
すぐ 後を追うよ。
We found Shino's Parasitic Insects!
We need to pursue immediately.
オス！
いつまでかかってんのよ。
Right.
What took you so long?!
ワリい。
ちょっと知り合いに会ってさ。
Sorry... I ran into someone I knew.
ウソに決まってるでしょ。
He's lying, of course.
こんなところに知り合いなんて
いるわけないんだから。
There's no way he'd run into
someone he knew out here.
なっ ホントにいたんだってばよ。
He was really there, I'm telling you!
これくらいの小ちゃい…。
A boy about this tall and...
フン 雁首揃えて情けないね。
Humph, you're a pitiful lot!
(麟児)面目ねえ。
ヤツら なかなかの手練で。
We're ashamed.
Those guys were quite skilled...
まあ そのおかげで
ヤツらの手の内見せてもらったよ。
Well, because of that,
we got a look at what they can do.
やっかいなのは カカシくらいだ。
Kakashi's about the only troublesome one.
まずは カカシの動きを止める。
The first thing we need to do
is stop Kakashi.
大蛇丸様の計画を➡
We can't let those guys interfere
with Orochimaru-sama's plans.
ヤツらに ジャマされるわけには
いかないからね。
(紅蓮)あとは私が…。
I'll see to the rest...
《仕掛けは上々》
The trap is looking good...
《八掛八方陣に仕込んだ
八角翠晶の種。
The seed of the Octangular Jade Crystal
placed in the 8 Trigrams
8 Square Formation.
コイツが輝くとき
翠晶の中の光はさまよい➡
When this shines, the light
inside the Jade Crystal
永久に外に出ることはない。
will bounce around,
trapped for all eternity.
花開け！ 晶遁 翠晶迷宮の術！
Blossom!
Crystal Style: Jade Crystal Labyrinth!
(カカシ)シノ！ どうだ 追えるか!?
Shino?! Can you follow it?!
(シノ)問題ない…。
No problem.
なぜなら 蟲の包囲網が
完成されていなかったのは➡
Because the only place where
the Parasitic Insects' net was not complete
唯一 この
十時の方向だけだからだ。
was in this ten o'clock direction.
(赤丸)ウウウ…。
(キバ)あぁ ヤツらの目的を
突き止める必要がありそうだぜ。
Yeah, looks like we'll have to
determine their objective.
それじゃ 行くぞ。
いや 待て。
- Then, let's go.
- No, hold on.
(キバ)なんだよ シノ！
ワンッ！
What is it, Shino?!
寄壊蟲の動きがおかしい…。
The Parasitic Insects are
behaving strangely...
まるで出口を見失っているようだ。
It's as though they can't
find their way out.
どういうことだよ。
What do you mean?
蟲たちの すべての感覚が失われ➡
How do I describe it...?
The Parasitic Insects seem to
have lost all of their senses
さまよっている…
というところか。
and seem to be wandering aimlessly.
(ヒナタ)幻術か何かなの？
Could it be some sort of Genjutsu?
ヤツら 物理攻撃しか
使ってこなかったぜ。
They didn't use anything
except physical attacks.
いや ただ単に仕掛けてこなかった
とも考えられる。
No, it's also possible that
they simply chose not to use it on us.
手の内を隠してるってことか？
You mean they kept their secrets hidden?
ヒナタ 封印術や
結界が張られていないか➡
Hinata, check to see if
there is a Sealing Jutsu or a barrier.
調べてくれ。
はい。
Will do.
白眼!!
Byakugan!
どうした ヒナタ！
What's the matter, Hinata?!
私たちの… 姿が… 無数に…。
Infinite... images... of us...
白眼が封じられた？
The Byakugan was overcome?
晶遁 翠晶鏡！
Crystal Style: Jade Crystal Mirror.
フフフ… 相変わらず 美しいね。
Lovely as always...
Jade Crystal Clone Jutsu.
翠晶分身の術！
どうやら 何かしらの結界の中に
閉じ込められているようだ。
Seems they were sealed
within some sort of barrier.
敵を寄壊蟲で
封じ込めていたつもりが…。
We thought we had the enemy sealed off
with the Parasitic Insects.
さらに その外郭を
封じられていたというわけか。
But their outer perimeter was further off,
is that it?
ウウ～ ワン!!
敵だ！
The enemy!
(カカシ)散!!
Scatter!
晶遁 翠晶刀!!
Crystal Style: Jade Crystal Blade!
《カカシ : 物質を結晶化する術か…。
So it's a Jutsu that crystallizes material...
空気中の成分すら
結晶化させるとしたら➡
If it crystallizes the moisture in the air,
攻撃の材料は無限大…》
there are an infinite number
of weapons to use for attacks.
この戦い 長引かせるわけには
いかないんでな。
We can't let this battle draw out.
コピー忍者のカカシ…➡
Kakashi the Copy Ninja...
それが あんたの写輪眼か…
でも ムダだ…。
So that's your Sharingan...
But it's no use.
私の晶遁は コピーできないよ。
My Crystal Style cannot be copied.
ダメ… やっぱり白眼は使えない。
It's no use! I can't use Byakugan.
アンタ 目がいいそうだね。 でもね
私の翠晶のなかでは光は屈折し➡
I hear you've got good eyes...
But inside my Jade Crystal,
light is refracted.
かえって
その目のよさが仇となる。
Your good eyesight works against you.
白眼が使えなくても！
I have more than just Byakugan!
フッ… 私と正面きって
やり合おうっての？
You want to fight me face-to-face?
その目を封じられて
どうしようってんだい？
What can you do with your eyes sealed?
《ずっと ずっと…➡
For a long time...
ナルト君に認めてもらおうと
一生懸命 修業を続けてきた》
I've trained as hard I could
so Naruto would acknowledge my ability.
そんなに死に急ぎたいのかい？
Are you that anxious to die?
《ネジ兄さんには及ばなくても
私だって…！
I might not be at
my cousin Neji's level, but I...
敵だけに集中して！》
Concentrate only on the enemy...
柔拳法 八卦三十二掌！
Gentle Fist 8 Trigrams 32 Palms!
八卦ニ掌！ 四掌！
8 Trigrams 2 Palms! 4 Palms!
八掌！
8 Palms!
十六掌！
16 Palms!
三十ニ掌！
32 Palms!
うっ…。
決まった。
It worked!
晶遁 翠晶牢の術！
Crystal Style: Jade Crystal Prison!
何だ？
ワン！
What's happening?!
どうした？
向こうが勝手に引きやがった。
ワン！
- What happened?
- She just up and left.
あぁ こっちもそうだ。
(カカシ)ヒナタは？
The same thing happened with me.
Where's Hinata?
(紅蓮)お前たちのお仲間は
ここだよ！
Here's your friend.
ヒナタ！
(カカシ)しまった！
Hinata!
Damn!
何だってばよ これは!?
What the hell is this?!
結晶… 敵の術に間違いないね。
Crystals...
This is unmistakably the enemy's Jutsu.
And it seems huge.
にしても
随分と大きなもののようだ。 サイ！
はい！ わかっています。
- Sai!
- Right! Gotcha.
やっぱりね。
(サイ)直径１キロは あると思います。
Just as I thought.
I think it's about a kilometer across.
１キロとはまた…
相当な使い手だ。
One kilometer...
It must be the work of
someone very skilled.
とっとと ぶっ壊すってばよ！
(ヤマト)ちょっと待て ナルト。
Let's break it down right away.
Hold on a minute, Naruto.
There's a kind of barrier here.
一種の結界のようだけど 何か
仕掛けがあるといけないからね。
We can't risk the possibility
that it's been rigged somehow...
大丈夫。 外側からの攻撃では
反応しないようだ。
It's okay. It doesn't react to
an attack from outside.
カカシ先輩たちは きっと
この中に閉じ込められている。
Kakashi-senpai and the others
must be trapped inside.
閉じ込められてるだけなら
いいけど…。
If they're only trapped inside, that's fine.
内部に何か
仕掛けがあるとしたら厄介よね。
But if there's a trap set up inside,
this is going to be trouble.
ヤマト隊長 大蛇丸のアジトに
潜入したときみてえに➡
Captain Yamato,
can't we bust down the wall
壁を壊すことはできねえのか？
the way we did when we snuck
into Orochimaru's hideout?
(ヤマト)残念ながら
この結晶っていうのは➡
I'm afraid that this crystal possesses
分子レベルで とても規則正しく
並んでいるんだよ。
an extremely tight structure
at the molecular level.
前の土壁とは違って
隙間なんてないんだ。
Unlike the clay wall,
there are no weak spots.
だけど 地中深くからなら…。
But... if we went from underground...
地中まで
すっぽり 結晶で包まれてる。
Even the ground itself is encased in crystal.
There are no weak spots at all.
まるで 隙がないな。
(サイ)かなりの強度のようだし➡
It appears very strong.
一点集中型の術でも
壊せそうにない。
It doesn't look like we could break it
with a Jutsu concentrated at one point.
(サクラ)そうね
これだけ大きいとなると➡
I agree...
With something this large,
the force would be dispersed equally,
与えた力が均等に広がって
攻撃力を弱めてしまう。
weakening the power of the attack.
うむ もっと広範囲に➡
Yes. It would have to be
a Jutsu that could do
強力なダメージを
与えられる術でないと…。
both widespread and powerful damage...
おもしれえ！
ダメ！ ナルト！
- Sounds like fun!
- You mustn't, Naruto!
大丈夫だってばよ サクラちゃん。
I'll be fine, Sakura.
I won't use that Jutsu.
あの術は使わねえ。
今 修業中の術を試させてくれ。
Let me try out a Jutsu
I've been working on!
ナルト…。
Naruto...
口寄せの術！
Summoning Jutsu!
(ガマ吉)よう！
(ガマ竜)呼んだ？
- Yo!
- We've been summoned!
えっ 口寄せ？
What? Summoning?
へぇ 口寄せできるんだ ナルト。
Oh... you can do
the Summoning Jutsu, Naruto?
(ヤマト)口寄せで何をする気だ？
What are you going to do
with Summoning Jutsu?
ヘヘヘ まぁ 見ててくれってばよ。
Just watch and see!
いいか まだ完成してねえけど
あれをやるしかねえ。
Here's what we're going to do!
We haven't perfected it yet,
but it's all we've got!
翠晶に閉じ込められた光は
外に出ることはできないのさ。
Light sealed inside the Jade Crystal
can never get out.
動くんじゃないよ！
Don't move!
アンタらが
これ以上つきまとうなら➡
If you guys follow us around any longer,
仲間は粉々に砕けて
光の粉になっちまうよ！
your friend will end up
as shattered shards of light!
準備オーケーだよ。
I'm ready to go.
いいか チャクラを流し込むタイミングは➡
Okay listen.
Use the timing we worked on earlier
to pour in the Chakra.
さっきの感じだってばよ。
(ガマ竜)うん。
Right.
いったい 何しようっていうの？
What are they going to do?
まずは お手並み拝見といこうか。
Well, let's see what they've got.
いくぜ ガマ竜！
Let's do it, Gamatatsu!
鼻から 思いきり息を吸う。
Inhale through the nose!
いったん ためて
一気に吐き出す！
Hold it in... then exhale it all at once!
今だ！
Now!
はぁ…
やっぱり意外性ナンバーワン忍者ね。
Just as I thought, he's the top Ninja
when it comes to doing the unexpected.
何やってんだってばよ ガマ竜！
What're you doing, Gamatatsu?!
ごめん チャクラ練るの忘れちゃった。
Sorry, I forgot to mold the Chakra...
こら ガマ竜！ おやつ抜きじゃぞ！
Come on!
Or no snacks for you, Gamatatsu!
よっしゃ！
気を取り直して もう１回！
Okay, get yourself together
and we'll try it again!
腹の中で チャクラを練って➡
Mold Chakra in your stomach
and inhale through the nose!
鼻から思いきり息を吸う。
(ガマ吉)いったん ためて
一気に吐き出す！
Hold it in... then exhale it out all at once.
今だ！ 風遁 ガマ鉄砲！
Now!
Wind Style: Toad Water Pistol!
やったってばよ！
We did it!
Oh my god! Oh my god!
oh my god oh my god
yesterday's mistake got me discouraged, but
kinou no shippai de kojiketatte
Thank you! Thank you!
gottsuanda gottsuanda
my new clothes got splashed with some sauce, wow
onyuu no fuku ni sousu ga hanete wao
don't mind, don't mind, if I stay feeling like this I'll have a tear in my eyes
donmai donmai shizunda mama ja namida mo my eyes
I may be hungry and angry
donna ni hangurii de angurii demo
but I'll grab a bowl to eat and start dancing!
donburi kutte danshingu
We'll always be pals my brother!
orera itsumo demo nakama daro burazaa
hit me with an upwind or strong wind or a storm I'm ready so come on!
tatoe gyarufuu kyoufuu arashi ga fuitemo bacchikoi kamon
we may be apart but we'll still be under the same sky
hanaretetemo onaji sora no shita de
so smile and hang on
saa waratte funbatte
lets do it do it do it do it
Bring it, bring it baby!
bacchikoi bacchikoi baby
even if morning doesn't come, yay yay
tatoe asa ga konakutatte yay yay
Bring it, bring it baby!
bacchikoi bacchikoi baby
we'll still watch the dream together, yay yay
kimi to tomo ni yume wo miru ze yay yay
Bring it, bring it baby!
bacchikoi bacchikoi baby
no matter what, don't ever, ever give up, yay yay
nani ga nandemo aa demo kou demo akirameru na yay yay
Bring it, bring it baby!
bacchikoi bacchikoi baby
morning will always come after night, yay yay
donna yoru mo asa wa kuru ze yay yay
nanananana
Next Episode
Naruto, was that...?
It's the new Jutsu
I made with the Pervy Sage.
By the way, Senpai,
looks like we're in a bad situation here.
Yeah, as you can see,
Hinata was taken as a hostage.
Gamatatsu, can you do
that one more time?
Sure, but what're you gonna do?
I have an idea. Let's go, Gamatatsu!
Yeah!
Wait, Naruto!
Collaboration Ninjutsu!
Wind Style: Toad Water Pistol!
The Target Appears
Next Time: "The Target Appears"
ナハハッ こつこつ貯めたお金で買った
中古のテレビ！
It took me a long time to
save up for this second-hand TV.
さっそく観るぞ！
サクラちゃんのニュース番組！
I can't wait to watch
Sakura-chan's news program!
(サクラ)それでは続きまして…。
サクラちゃん！
On to the next topic...
- We have an advisory.
- There's Sakura-chan!
もう みんなは
知ってるわよね 地デジ。
I'm sure all of you are aware...
that we're going digital.
ち… 地デジ？
Gi? Digi...?
(ヤマト)2011年７月24日までに
アナログ放送が終了して➡
All analog broadcasts will end
by July 24, 2011
地上デジタル放送に変わります。
and every station will switch
over to digital broadcasts.
現在 アナログテレビで観てる人は➡
All of you currently
watching on analog television sets
デジタルチューナーなどの準備が必要よ。
じゃないと➡
will need to get digital tuners.
テレビが観られなくなっちゃうの。
なに!?
Otherwise, you won't be
able to watch any programs.
What?!
でもね 地デジに切り替わると➡
But when we switch over to digital,
きれいな画質 クリアな音質で➡
you'll be able to enjoy Naruto Shippuden
with even better screen and audio clarity.
『NARUTO疾風伝』が
楽しめるってわけ。
(角都)これが人柱力の…。
おぉ すげえ！
- This is the power of the Jinchuriki.
- Wow, that's amazing!
出たな 暁！
これでも くらえ！ 螺旋丸！
So you've appeared Akatsuki!
Eat this!
- Rasengan!
間違っても 画面に向かって
螺旋丸なんか打ち込まないでね。
Please don't make a mistake and
release a Rasengan at the monitor!
サクラちゃん 遅いってばよ…。
Sakura-chan... Your warning is too late.